[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the name of the hobbit protagonist in 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Frodo Baggins", "Samwise Gamgee", "Bilbo Baggins", "Meriadoc Brandybuck"],
    "correct_option": "Bilbo Baggins"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which dwarf leads the company of dwarves on the quest to reclaim Erebor?",
    "options": ["Thorin Oakenshield", "Gimli", "Fili", "Kili"],
    "correct_option": "Thorin Oakenshield"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What is the name of the wizard who assists Bilbo and the dwarves on their journey?",
    "options": ["Radagast the Brown", "Gandalf the Grey", "Saruman the White", "Alatar the Blue"],
    "correct_option": "Gandalf the Grey"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which dragon is the main antagonist in 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Smaug", "Glaurung", "Ancalagon", "Scatha the Worm"],
    "correct_option": "Smaug"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What is the name of the Elvenking who rules the woodland realm in Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Galadriel", "Thranduil", "Celeborn", "Legolas"],
    "correct_option": "Thranduil"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which character from 'The Lord of the Rings' trilogy makes an appearance in 'The Hobbit' movies?",
    "options": ["Aragorn", "Frodo Baggins", "Gimli", "Legolas"],
    "correct_option": "Legolas"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What is the name of the magical ring that Bilbo finds and uses to escape from Gollum?",
    "options": ["The One Ring", "The Ring of Power", "The Precious", "The Ring of Sauron"],
    "correct_option": "The One Ring"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Who is the leader of the company of dwarves in 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Dwalin", "Thorin Oakenshield", "Oin", "Dori"],
    "correct_option": "Thorin Oakenshield"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What is the name of the giant spiders that attack Bilbo and the dwarves in Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Shelob", "Ungoliant", "Arachne", "Mirkwood Spiders"],
    "correct_option": "Mirkwood Spiders"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which ancient dwarf kingdom do the dwarves aim to reclaim from Smaug?",
    "options": ["Khazad-dûm", "Erebor", "Iron Hills", "Lonely Mountain"],
    "correct_option": "Lonely Mountain"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is the name of Bilbo's home in the Shire?",
    "options": ["Bag End", "Green Dragon Inn", "Brandy Hall", "Tookburrow"],
    "correct_option": "Bag End"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Who is the master of Laketown in 'The Desolation of Smaug'?",
    "options": ["Bard", "Thranduil", "Alfrid Lickspittle", "Master of Lakeville"],
    "correct_option": "Bard"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "What is the name of the giant bear that assists Thorin and company in the Battle of the Five Armies?",
    "options": ["Beorn", "Bolg", "Azog", "Radagast"],
    "correct_option": "Beorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What is the name of Thorin Oakenshield's sword?",
    "options": ["Glamdring", "Orcrist", "Sting", "Foe-Hammer"],
    "correct_option": "Orcrist"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Which member of the company of dwarves is known for his skill in crafting and invention?",
    "options": ["Bombur", "Bifur", "Ori", "Nori"],
    "correct_option": "Ori"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "What is the name of the city where the dwarves initially plan to reclaim their treasure from Smaug?",
    "options": ["Dale", "Esgaroth", "Erebor", "Rivendell"],
    "correct_option": "Erebor"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Who is the leader of the eagles that help Gandalf and the company of dwarves?",
    "options": ["Gwaihir", "Landroval", "Thorondor", "Meneldor"],
    "correct_option": "Gwaihir"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What is the name of the mysterious Necromancer who turns out to be Sauron?",
    "options": ["Saruman", "Sauron" , "Gandalf", "Azog"],
    "correct_option": "Sauron"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Which ancient Elven blade does Thorin wield during the Battle of the Five Armies?",
    "options": ["Glamdring", "Orcrist", "Sting", "Andúril"],
    "correct_option": "Orcrist"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What is the name of the river that flows near the Elven kingdom of Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Anduin", "Entwash", "Celduin", "Lhûn"],
    "correct_option": "Celduin"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Elven blade that Gandalf wields in 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Glamdring", "Sting", "Andúril", "Narsil"],
    "correct_option": "Glamdring"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which character is known for his skill in archery and becomes a key figure in the Battle of the Five Armies?",
    "options": ["Bard", "Dwalin", "Balin", "Fíli"],
    "correct_option": "Bard"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "What is the name of the shape-shifter encountered by Bilbo and the dwarves in Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Beorn", "Tom Bombadil", "Skin-changer", "Gandalf"],
    "correct_option": "Beorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "In 'The Battle of the Five Armies,' what powerful weapon does Thorin Oakenshield wield?",
    "options": ["Glamdring", "Orcrist", "Foe-Hammer", "Dragon Slayer"],
    "correct_option": "Foe-Hammer"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "What is the name of the mysterious, ancient city that the company of dwarves ventures into before reaching the Lonely Mountain?",
    "options": ["Dale", "Rivendell", "Khazad-dûm", "Dol Guldur"],
    "correct_option": "Dol Guldur"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Which member of the company of dwarves is skilled in playing musical instruments and entertains the company?",
    "options": ["Bofur", "Bifur", "Bombur", "Ori"],
    "correct_option": "Bofur"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "What is the name of the giant eagle who rescues Bilbo and the dwarves from the treetops in Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Gwaihir", "Landroval", "Thorondor", "Meneldor"],
    "correct_option": "Gwaihir"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "What is the name of Thorin Oakenshield's father?",
    "options": ["Thrain", "Thror", "Dain", "Balin"],
    "correct_option": "Thror"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Which creature is known for its ability to change its size and appearance and is encountered in Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Boggart", "Changeling", "Necromancer", "Skin-changer"],
    "correct_option": "Skin-changer"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Elven blade that Bilbo acquires in the troll's hoard?",
    "options": ["Glamdring", "Orcrist", "Sting", "Andúril"],
    "correct_option": "Sting"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Elven blade that Legolas wields in 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Orcrist", "Andúril", "Sting", "Daggers of Legolas"],
    "correct_option": "Orcrist"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "What treasure does Smaug primarily hoard in the Lonely Mountain?",
    "options": ["Gold", "Jewels", "Weapons", "Books"],
    "correct_option": "Gold"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "What is the name of the river that flows through the town of Esgaroth (Lake-town)?",
    "options": ["Celduin", "Anduin", "Lhûn", "Bruinen"],
    "correct_option": "Celduin"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Which character is known for his love of fireworks and pyrotechnics?",
    "options": ["Gandalf", "Radagast", "Bombur", "Saruman"],
    "correct_option": "Gandalf"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "What is the name of the elf who develops a romantic interest in the dwarf Kíli?",
    "options": ["Tauriel", "Galadriel", "Arwen", "Éowyn"],
    "correct_option": "Tauriel"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "In 'The Desolation of Smaug,' what is the name of the enchanted forest the company of dwarves enters?",
    "options": ["Mirkwood", "Lothlórien", "Fangorn", "Old Forest"],
    "correct_option": "Mirkwood"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "What is the name of the fortress where Gandalf is imprisoned by the Necromancer?",
    "options": ["Barad-dûr", "Orthanc", "Dol Guldur", "Minas Morgul"],
    "correct_option": "Dol Guldur"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "What is the name of the town destroyed by Smaug before the events of 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Esgaroth", "Dale", "Bree", "Lake-town"],
    "correct_option": "Dale"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Which character possesses the ability to shape-shift into a bear?",
    "options": ["Gandalf", "Beorn", "Radagast", "Tom Bombadil"],
    "correct_option": "Beorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "What is the name of the Elven kingdom located in Mirkwood?",
    "options": ["Rivendell", "Lórien", "Eregion", "Thranduil's Realm"],
    "correct_option": "Thranduil's Realm"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Elven blade that Bilbo uses in the Battle of the Five Armies?",
    "options": ["Glamdring", "Orcrist", "Sting", "Foe-Hammer"],
    "correct_option": "Sting"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Who is the leader of the company of dwarves when Thorin Oakenshield is incapacitated?",
    "options": ["Fíli", "Dwalin", "Balin", "Kíli"],
    "correct_option": "Kíli"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "What is the name of the necromancer who is later revealed to be Sauron?",
    "options": ["Radagast", "Saruman", "Azog", "Sauron"],
    "correct_option": "Sauron"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "What event leads to Thorin Oakenshield's descent into madness during 'The Battle of the Five Armies'?",
    "options": ["The death of Fíli", "The destruction of Lake-town", "The death of Kíli", "The arrival of the Eagles"],
    "correct_option": "The death of Fíli"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Elven blade that Legolas wields?",
    "options": ["Orcrist", "Sting", "Glamdring", "Thranduil's Blade"],
    "correct_option": "Glamdring"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Who is known as the \"Skin-changer\" in 'The Hobbit'?",
    "options": ["Beorn", "Radagast", "Tom Bombadil", "Thranduil"],
    "correct_option": "Beorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "What is the name of the town that Legolas and Tauriel visit in 'The Desolation of Smaug'?",
    "options": ["Esgaroth", "Dale", "Lake-town", "Dol Guldur"],
    "correct_option": "Lake-town"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "What creature helps Bilbo and the dwarves escape from the wood elves' prison barrels in 'The Desolation of Smaug'?",
    "options": ["Beorn", "Gwaihir", "Radagast", "Bard"],
    "correct_option": "Beorn"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "What is the name of the river that Bilbo and the dwarves use to travel to Lake-town in barrels?",
    "options": ["Anduin", "Lhûn", "Celduin", "Bruinen"],
    "correct_option": "Celduin"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "What is the name of the goblin king encountered in the Misty Mountains?",
    "options": ["Gollum", "Azog", "Bolg", "Great Goblin"],
    "correct_option": "Great Goblin"
  }
]
